Dearborn, Frederick M. (Frederick Myers), b. 1876, collector. Frederick M. Dearborn collection of military and political Americana, Part II: The Civil War and the Confederacy, 1832-1915 (MS Am 1649.24): Guide.
Frederick M. Dearborn collection of military and political Americana, Part II: The Civil War and the Confederacy,
- Ould, Robert. A.L.s. to Roswell V. Booth; Richmond, 23 Jun 1863., (711); 1s.(2p.)
- Ould, Robert. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Richmond, 20 Mar 1863., (712); 1s.(4p.)
- Ould, Robert. A.L.s. to George A. Trenholm; Richmond, 17 Mar 1865., (713); 1s.(2p.)
- Page, Pawhatan R. A.L.s. to Maj. L. O. Chestney; Chaffins Farm, 6 Aug 1863., (714); 1s.(3p.)
  Report of attack on gunboats at Deep Bottom.
- Page, Richard Lucian, 1807-1901. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Norfolk, 25 Jun 1871., (715); 1s.(2p.)
- Palmer, Joseph Benjamin, 1825-1890. A.L.s. to Samuel Cooper; Asheville, 6 May 1864., (716); 1s.(2p.)
- Parker, William W. A.L.s. to Maj. [] Griswold; near Chesterfield Depot, 17 Mar 1863., (717); 1s.(4p.)
- Parsons, Mosby Monroe, 1822-1865. MS.L.s. to Col. M. S. Clark; [n.p.] 13 May 1861., (718); 1s.(4p.)
- Parsons, Mosby Monroe, 1822-1865. A.L.s. to Thomas Lowndes Snead; Camp Kirby Smith, Ark., 17 Jun 1864., (719); 1s.(3p.)
- Parsons, Mosby Monroe, 1822-1865. A.L.s. to Gen. M. Jeff Thompson; Des Arc, Ark., 11 Apr 1862., (720); 1s.(3p.)
- Parsons, Mosby Monroe, 1822-1865. MS.D.s.; Camp Anderson, 1 May 1863., (721); 1s.(2p.)
- Patton, Robert M. A.L.s. to [Jonathan Worth]; Montgomery, 24 Nov 1866., (722); 1s.(2p.)
- Payne, William Henry [Fitzhugh], 1830-1904. A.L.s. to Col. [] Smith; Fauquin Springs, 30 Apr 1861., (723); 1s.(2p.)
- Paxton, Elisha Franklin, 1828-1863. MS.L.s. to Thomas Jonathan Jackson; Harpers Ferry, 1 May [1861?]., (724)
- Peane, James H. A.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Chaffins Farm, 24 Mar 1863., (725); 1s.(2p.)
- Peck, William Raine, 1818-1871. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (726); 1s.(1p.)
- Pegram, John, 1832-1865. A.L.s. to John Cabell Breckinridge, 13 Dec 1862., (727); 1s.(4p.)
- Pegram, John, 1832-1865. MS.L. (unsigned transcript) to Joseph Wheeler; [n.p.] 20 Oct 1862., (728); 1s.(1p.)
- Pegram, John, 1832-1865. A.L.s. to []; Fernando de Taos, N.M, 30 Dec 1860., (729); 1s.(1p.)
- Pegram, John, 1832-1865. A.L.s. to []; Lexington, Ky., 14 Sep 1862., (730); 1s.(2p.)
- Pegram, Robert B. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (731); 1s.(1p.)
- Pemberton, John Clifford, 1814-1881. A.L.s. to James Chesnut; [], 22 Mar 1862., (732); 1s.(3p.)
- Pemberton, John Clifford, 1814-1881. 2 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Jackson, 16 Feb 1863., (733); 1s.(4p.)
  - Demopolis, 29 Jul 1863., (734); 1s.(3p.)
- Pemberton, John Clifford, 1814-1881. A.L.s. to [James Birdseye] McPherson; 8 Jul 1865., (735); 1s.(2p.)
- Pendleton, A. S. 2 MS.D.s.:
  - [N.p.] 25 Jul 1862., (736); 1s.(2p.)
  - [N.p.] 9 Jan 1863., (737); 1s.(2p.)
- Pendleton, William Nelson, 1809-1883. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; [n.p.], (738); 1s.(3p.)
- Pendleton, William Nelson, 1809-1883. A.L.s. to []; Harpers Ferry, 6 Jun 1861., (739); 1s.(1p.)
- Perry, Edward Aylesworth, 1831-1889. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Pensacola, 16 Apr 1872., (740); 1s.(1p.)
- Perry, Madison Starke. A.L.s. to []; Charleston, 28 Jul 1860., (741); 1s.(1p.)
- Perry, Madison Starke. MS.L. (telegram) to Jefferson Davis; Tallahassee, [n.d.], (742); 1s.(1p.)
- Perry, William Flank, 1823-1901. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Bowling Green, 8 Sep 1890., (743); 2s.(2p.)
- Pettigrew, James Johnston, 1828-1863. A.L.s. to States Rights Gist; Fort Morris, 20 Jan 1861., (744); 1s.(2p.)
- Pettigrew, James Johnston, 1828-1863. MS.D.s. to D. F. Jameson; Fort Morris, 15 Jan 1861., (745); 2s.(8p.)
- Pettigrew, James Johnston, 1828-1863. MS.D.s.; Morris Island, 18 Jan 1861., (746); 2s.(2p.)
- Pettus, Edmund Winston, 1821-1907. A.L.s. to Joseph Wheeler; Selma, 6 Nov 1875., (747); 1s.(4p.)
- Pettus, John G. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Jackson, 11 Jun 1862., (748); 1s.(3p.)
- Pettus, John Jones. 2 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Jackson, 19 Jun 1862., (749); 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 16 Jul 1862., (750); 1s.(3p.)
- Pettus, John Jones. Printed D.s.; Jackson, 2 Oct 1860., (751); 1s.(1p.)
- Phifer, Charles W. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Dallas, 26 May 1874., (752); 1s.(2p.)
- Pickett, George Edward, 1825-1875. A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Petersburg, 6 Apr 1864., (753); 1s.(1p.)
- Pickett, George Edward, 1825-1875. A.L.s. to []; [n.p.] 9 Jul 1861., (754); 1s.(1p.)
- Pickins, Francis Wilkinson, 1805-1869. 2 MS.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis:
  - [Columbia] 31 Oct 1861., (755); 2s.(3p.)
  - Columbia, 8 Aug 1862., (756); 1s.(3p.)
- Pierpont, Francis Harrison, 1814-1899. MS.L.s. to Schuyler Colfax; Richmond, 8 Dec 1865., (757); 1s.(1p.)
- Pike, Albert, 1809-1891. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Fort McCullogh, 10 Jun 1862., (758); 1s.(3p.)
- Pillow, Gideon Johnson, 1806-1878. A.L.s. to Gen. [] Bradley; [n.p.] 27 May 1861., (759); 1s.(1p.)
- Pillow, Gideon Johnson, 1806-1878. A.L.s. to Gen. M. Jeff Thompson; Columbus, 26 Nov 1861., (760); 1s.(2p.)
- Pillow, Gideon Johnson, 1806-1878. A.L.s. [fragment] to Gen. [] Snead; [n.p.] 28 May 1861., (761); 1s.(2p.)
- Pleasants, H. C. A.L.s. to A. C. Mathews; near Little Rock, 14 Apr 1863., (762); 1s.(2p.)
- Polignac, C. J. A.L.s. to Edward Porter Alexander; Richmond, 24 Jan 1863., (763); 1s.(3p.)
- Polignac, C. J. A.L.s. to Samuel Bell Maxey; Tupelo, 20 Jun 1862., (764); 1s.(2p.)
- Polk, Leonidas, 1806-1864. MS.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Tulahoma, 30 Jan 1863., (765); 1s.(3p.)
- Polk, Leonidas, 1806-1864. 3 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Columbus, Ky., 6 Nov 1861., (766); 1s.(3p.)
  - [N.p.] 27 Apr 1863., (767); 1s.(1p.)
  - [N.p.] Oct [1863]., (768); 1s.(3p.)
- Polk, Leonidas, 1806-1864. A.L.s. to []; Columbus, 6 Nov 1861., (769); 1s.(2p.)
- Polk, Lucius Eugene, 1833-1892. A.L.s. to []; [n.p.] 12 Jul 1887., (770); 3s.(3p.)
- Preston, John Smith, 1809-1881. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Columbia, 28 Dec 1864., (771); 1s.(4p.)
- Preston, William, 1816-1887. 2 MS.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis:
  - Richmond, 9 Jan 1864., (772); 1s.(1p.)
  - Havana, 2 Jun 1864., (773); 1s.(4p.)
- Preston, William, 1816-1887. A.L.s. to Maj. [] Hayden; [n.p.] 24 Nov 1863., (774); 1s.(3p.)
- Preston, William, 1816-1887. A.L.s. to William Preston Johnston; Richmond, 12 Dec 1864., (775); 1s.(3p.)
- Preston, William, 1816-1887. MS.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon; Richmond, 9 Sep 1864., (776); 2s.(4p.)
- Price, Sterling, 1809-1867. MS.L.s. to John B. Clark; Tupelo, 19 Aug 1862., (777); 2s.(6p.)
- Pryor, Roger Atkinson, 1828-1919. MS.L. (telegram) to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Richmond, 10 Feb 1862., (778); 1s.(1p.)
- Pryor, Roger Atkinson, 1828-1919. Endorsement s.; [n.p., n.d.], (779); 1s.(1p.)
  On foot of letter by W. Miller to John Henry Winder.
- Quarles, William Andrew, 1825-1893. Endorsement s.; [n.p.] 24 Aug 1864., (780); 1s.(1p.)
- Rains, Gabriel James, 1803-1881. A.L.s. to John Letcher; Richmond, 13 May 1863., (781); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto:
  - Verso:
- Rains, Gabriel James, 1803-1881. A.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon; Richmond, 15 Apr 1863., (782); 1s.(4p.)
- Rains, George Washington, 1817-1898. A.L.s. to Thomas Jordan; Augusta, 23 Oct 1862., (783); 1s.(2p.)
- Rams, James E. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (784); 1s.(1p.)
- Randal, Horace. Endorsement s.; []; 22 Sep 1863., (785); 1s.(1p.)
- Randolph, George Wythe, 1818-1867. MS.L. (telegram) to [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard; Richmond, 28 May 1862., (786); 1s.(2p.)
- Randolph, George Wythe, 1818-1867. MS.L. (telegram) to Braxton Bragg; Corinth, 2 Apr 1862., (787); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by Braxton Bragg.
- Randolph, George Wythe, 1818-1867. 7 letters to Jefferson Davis:
  - Suffolk, 20 Mar 1862., (788); 1s.(2p.)
  - Richmond, 29 May 1862., (789); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 17 Jun 1862., (790); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 3 Sep 1862., (791); 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 23 Sep 1862., (792); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 25 Sep 1862., (793); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 26 Sep 1862., (794); 2s.(3p.)
- Randolph, George Wythe, 1818-1867. MS.L.s. to Edward Johnson; Richmond, 22 Apr 1862., (795); 1s.(1p.)
- Randolph, George Wythe, 1818-1867. MS.L. (telegram) to Samuel Jones; Richmond, 30 Apr 1862., (796); 1s.(2p.)
- Randolph, George Wythe, 1818-1867. MS.L. (telegram) to John Letcher; Richmond, 18 Oct 1862., (797); 1s.(2p.)
- Ransom, Matthew Whitaker, 1826-1904. A.L.s. to Seymour H. Ransom; City of Mexico, 8 Oct 1895., (798); 1s.(1p.)
- Ransom, Robert, 1828-1892. MS.L. (telegram) to [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard; Richmond, 31 May 1864., (799); 1s.(1p.)
- Ransom, Robert, 1828-1892. 2 A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg:
  - Near Drewrys Bluff, 10 May 1864., (800); 1s.(2p.)
  - Richmond, 19 May 1864., (801); 1s.(2p.)
- Ransom, Robert, 1828-1892. A.L.s. to Capt. [] Chism; Drewry's Farm; 16 May 1864., (802); 1s.(2p.)
- Ransom, Robert, 1828-1892. MS.L.s. to Samuel Cooper; Richmond, 22 Aug 1864., (803); 1s.(3p.)
- Ransom, Robert, 1828-1892. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; near Kinston, N.C., 1 Apr 1862., (804); 1s.(4p.)
- Ransom, Robert, 1828-1892. A.L.s. to Maj. [] Parker; Richmond, 30 Apr 1864., (805); 1s.(4p.)
- Reagan, John Henninger, 1818-1905. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Richmond, 6 Jan 1865., (806); 1s.(3p.)
- Rector, Henry Massey, 1816-1899. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Little Rock, 20 Mar 1861., (807); 1s.(1p.)
- Reid, John C. A.D.s. [n.p., n.d.], (808); 1s.(2p.)
- Reid, Peter C. A.L.s. to George Wythe Randolph; Orange C. H., 21 Jul 1862., (809); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by Randolph.
- Reynolds, Alexander Welch, 1816-1876. A.L.s. to Maj. []; Alexandria, 20 Oct 1873., (810); 1s.(1p.)
- Reynolds, Arthur E. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; near Granada, 20 Jan 1863., (811); 1s.(4p.)
- Reynolds, Daniel Harris, 1832-1902. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Lake Village, Ark., 4 Mar 1872., (812); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Reynolds, Thomas C. 3 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Memphis, 3 Jun 1861., (813); 1s.(2p.)
  - New Madrid, 19 Aug 1861., (814); 2s.(8p.)
  - Near Calhoun's Mill, S.C., 17 Aug 1862., (815); 1s.(4p.)
- Rhett, T. S. A.L.s. to Col. Joseph Christmas Ives; Richmond, 18 Jul 1862., (816); 1s.(2p.)
- Rhett, T. S. A.L.s. to John Henry Winder; [n.p.] 30 Jul 1862., (817); 1s.(2p.)
- Richardson, Robert Vinkler, 1820-1870. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (818); 1s.(1p.)
  With it a letter from James Richardson to Charles Colcock Jones concerning Gen. Richardson.
- Ripley, Rosewell Sabine, 1818-1867. 3 A.L.s. to Francis Wilkinson Pickens:
  - Fort Moultrie, 2 Jan 1861., (819); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 3 Jan 1861., (820); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 4 Jan 1861., (821); 1s.(2p.)
- Ripley, Rosewell Sabine, 1818-1867. MS.D.s.; Charleston, 12 Dec 1862., (822); 1s.(4p.)
- Rives, W. C. A.L.s. to Robert Edward Lee; Castle Hill, 2 May 1861., (823); 1s.(3p.)
- Roane, John Seldon, 1817-1867. A.L.s. to Col. []; Little Rock, 26 Feb 1863., (824); 1s.(2p.)
- Roberts, William Paul, 1841-1910. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Gatesville, N.C., 7 Aug 1871., (825); 1s.(3p.)
- Robertson, Beverly Holcombe, 1827-1910. A.L.s. to William Edmonson Jones; [n.p.] 29 Apr 1863., (826); 1s.(1p.)
- Robertson, Beverly Holcombe, 1827-1910. A.L.s. to Henry Alexander Wise, [n.p.] 7 Jan 1864., (827); 1s.(2p.)
- Robertson, Felix Huston, 1839-1928. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Waco, 28 Jan 1892., (828); 1s.(1p.)
- Robertson, Felix Huston, 1839-1928. A.L.s. to Gen. []; near Saltville, Va., 6 Oct 1864., (829); 2s.(6p.)
- Robertson, Jerome Bonaparte, 1815-1891. A.L.s. to Joseph A. Magle; [n.p.] 18 Aug [18--?], (830); 1s.(1p.)
- Roddey, Philip Dale, 1826-1897. A.L.s. to [Braxton] Bragg; Notasulga, 28 Jul 1864., (831); 1s.(2p.)
- Roddey, Philip Dale, 1826-1897. A.L.s. to William L. Snead; [n.p.] 14 Aug 1862., (832); 1s.(4p.)
- Rodes, Robert Emmett, 1829-1864. A.L.s. to Maj. Edwin A. Osborne; [n.p., n.d.], (833); 1s.(1p.)
- Rodes, Robert Emmett, 1829-1864. MS.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon; [n.p.] 21 Jan 1864., (834); 1s.(3p.)
- Rodes, Robert Emmett, 1829-1864. Endorsement s.; [n.p.] 27 Apr 1862., (835); 1s.(1p.)
- Ross, Laurence Sullivan, 1838-1898. A.L.s. to Dabney Herndon Maury; Camp Rodgers, Miss., 25 Oct 1862., (836); 1s.(3p.)
- Ross, Peter F. A.L.s. to Gen. [Charles W.] Phifer; Camp Maury, Miss., 25 Jun 1862., (837); 1s.(2p.)
- Rosser, Thomas Lafayette, 1836-1910. A.L.s. to Belmont Perry; Charlottesville, 2 Sep 1896., (838); 1s.(1p.) env.
- Rudler, Anthony F. A.L.s. to Col. George William Brent; Tyner's Station, 5 Aug 1863., (839); 1s.(2p.)
- Ruggles, Daniel, 1810-1897. A.L.s. to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Grenada, Miss., 17 Jun 1862., (840); 1s.(2p.)
- Ruggles, Daniel, 1810-1897. MS.L.s. to Col. [] Hardee; Port Hudson, 16 Aug 1862., (841); 1s.(2p.)
- Ruggles, Daniel, 1810-1897. A.L.s. to Col. [] Orr; Jackson, 7 Oct 1863., (842); 1s.(1p.)
- Ruggles, Daniel, 1810-1897. A.L.s. to Col. [] Shelby; Grenada, Miss., 14 Jun 1862., (843); 1s.(2p.)
- Ruggles, Daniel, 1810-1897. MS.D.s.; Fort McIntosh, Tex., Mar 1856., (844); 1s.(1p.)
- Ruggles, Daniel, 1810-1897. MS.D.s.; Frederiksburg, Va., 11 May 1861., (845); 1s.(2p.)
- Ruggles, Daniel, 1810-1897. MS.D.s.; Fredericksburg, 5 Jun 1861., (846); 1s.(2p.)
- Russell, Alfred A. A.L.s. to Capt. [] Walworth; [n.p.] 13 Jul 1863., (847); 1s.(2p.)
- Rust, Albert, 1818-1870. A.L.s. to Henry Rootes Jackson; [n.p.] Jul [1861?], (848); 1s.(2p.)
- Rust, Albert, 1818-1870. Printed D.s.; Memphis, 28 Apr 1862., (849); 1s.(2p.)
- Sale, John B. A.L.s. to Simon Bolivar Buckner; Richmond, 25 Apr 1864., (849.1); 1s.(2p.)
- Sale, John B. A.L.s. to Samuel Cooper; Richmond, 12 Apr 1864., (850); 1s.(1p.)
- Sale, John B. 2 A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis:
  - Richmond, 19 Nov 1864., (851); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 26 Jan 1865., (852); 1s.(1p.)
- Sanders, John Coldwell Calhoun, 1840-1864. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (853); 1s.(1p.)
  Enclosed in letter from W. H. Sanders to Charles Colcock Jones.
- Scott, Thomas Moore, 1829-1876. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Meusson Station, 30 May 1872., (854); 1s.(1p.)
- Scott, Thomas Moore, 1829-1876. A.L.s. to [Leonidas] Polk; Memphis, 26 Mar 1862., (855); 1s.(1p.)
- Scurry, William Read, 1821-1864. Endorsement s.; [n.p.] 14 Feb 1864., (856); 1s.(1p.)
- Sears, Claudius Wistar, 1817-1891. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Oxford, 22 Apr 1872., (857); 1s.(1p.)
- Seddon, James Alexander, 1815-1880. 3 letters s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Richmond, 26 Aug 1864., (858); 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 27 Oct 1864., (859); 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 3 Dec 1864., (860); 1s.(2p.)
- Seddon, James Alexander, 1815-1880. MS.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Richmond, 6 Mar 1863., (861); 1s.(2p.)
- Semmes, Raphael, 1809-1877. A.L.s. to S.D. Bashe; Washington, 9 Sep 1859., (862); 1s.(1p.)
- Semmes, Raphael, 1809-1877. A.L.s. to James Murray Mason; near Southhampton, 1 Jul 1864., (863); 1s.(2p.)
- Sharp, B. W. A.L. (unsigned exerpt) to Gideon Johnson Pillow; Columbus, Ky., 27 May 1861., (864); 1s.(1p.)
  Part of the exerpt is in the hand of Gen. Pillow.
- Sharp, Jacob Hunter, 1833-1907. A.L.s. to []; Columbus, 3 May 1872., (865); 1s.(1p.)
- Sharp, Thomas H. MS.D.s.; near Bridge Port, Ala., 19 Aug 1863., (866); 1s.(2p.)
- Shelby, Joseph Orville, 1830-1897. 2 A.L.s. to Col. L. A. Madean:
  - Powhattan, 13 Sep 1864., (867); 1s.(2p.)
  - [N.p.] 2 Oct 1864., (868); 1s.(2p.)
- Shelby, Charles Miller, 1833-1907. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (869); 1s.(1p.)
- Shorter, John Gill, 1818-1872. 6 MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Montgomery, 18 Jul 1862., (870); 2s.(4p.)
  - Same, 2 Aug 1862., (871); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 3 Dec 1862., (872); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 6 Apr 1863., (873); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 6 May 1863., (874); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 8 Aug 1863., (875); 1s.(3p.)
- Shoup, Francis Asbury, 1834-1896. A.L.s. to Maj. [] Smith; [n.p.] 30 Aug 1864., (876); 1s.(2p.)
- Simms, James Phillip, 1837-1887. A.L.s. to [Mrs. James Phillip Simms]; Richmond, 17 Jun 1864., (877); 1s.(2p.)
- Slack, William Yarnel, 1816-1862. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (878); 1s.(1p.)
- Slaughter, James Edwin, 1827-1901. MS.L. (telegram) to [Daniel] Ruggles; [n.p.] 1862., (879); 1s.(1p.)
  With reply by Ruggles.
- Slaughter, James Edwin, 1827-1901. A.L.s. to Daniel Ruggles; Jackson, 1862., (880); 1s.(1p.)
- Slidell, John, 1793-1871. 2 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - New Orleans, 24 Apr 1861., (881); 1s.(2p.)
  - Paris, 14 Jan 1864., (882); 1s.(3p.)
- Smith, Gustavus Woodson, 1822-1896. A.L.s. to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Centreville, 14 Nov 1861., (883); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by Beauregard.
- Smith, Gustavus Woodson, 1822-1896. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Richmond, 23 Feb 1863., (884); 3s.(12p.)
- Smith, J. Tipton. A.L.s. to Maj. D.E. Hager; near Louisburg, Tenn., 4 May 1863., (885); 1s.(2p.)
- Smith, James Argyle, 1831-1901. A.L.s. to Marcus Joseph Wright; Atlanta, 25 Mar 1864., (886); 1s.(1p.)
- Smith, Morgan Lewis, 1821-1874. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; Vicksburg, 23 Dec 1862., (887); 1s.(1p.)
- Smith, Morgan Lewis, 1821-1874. A.L.s. to Ulysses Simpson Grant; Vicksburg, 27 Jul 1865., (888); 1s.(2p.)
- Smith, Morgan Lewis, 1821-1874. A.L.s. to St. [] McDonald; [n.p.] 21 Apr 1862., (889); 1s.(1p.)
- Smith, Morgan Lewis, 1821-1874. MS.L. (telegram) to [Daniel] Ruggles; Vicksburg, 29 Sep 1862., (890); 1s.(2p.)
- Smith, Norman W. A.L.s. to Maj. Kinloch Falciner; Macon, 17 Sep 1864., (891); 1s.(2p.)
- Smith, Preston, 1823-1863. A.L.s. to Maj. George Williamson; [n.p.] 17 Jun 1862., (892); 1s.(2p.)
- Smith, Thomas Benton, 1838-1923. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Nashville, 8 Mar 1874., (893); 1s.(1p.)
  - Recto, letter
  - Portrait of Thomas Benton Smith, recto
  - Portrait of Thomas Benton Smith, verso
- Smith, William, 1797-1887. MS.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Richmond, 6 Jun 1864., (894); 1s.(2p.)
- Smith, William, 1797-1887. 3 MS.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]:
  - Richmond, 24 Oct 1864., (895); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 16 Dec 1864., (896); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 21 Feb 1865., (897); 1s.(2p.)
- Smith, William, 1797-1887. MS.L.s. to the Senate and House of Representatives of the Confederate States; Richmond, 19 May 1864., (898); 1s.(1p.)
- Smith, William, 1797-1887. A.L.s. to Col. David Urquhart; Richmond, 28 May 1864., (899); 1s.(2p.)
- Smith, William Duncan, 1825-1862. Printed D.s.; Austin, 26 Dec 1848., (900); 1s.(2p.)
- Smith, William Duncan, 1825-1862. MS.L. (unsigned copy) to Henry Constantine Wayne; Milledgeville, 19 Jan 1861., (901); 1s.(1p.)
- Smith, William Taylor. A.L.s. to Capt. W. F. Lynch; Pratt's Point, 31 May 1861., (902); 1s.(3p.)
- Sneed, John L. T. A.L.s. to [Gideon Johnson] Pillow; [n.p.] 30 May 1861., (903); 1s.(1p.)
- Sorrel, Gilbert Moxley, 1838-1901. A.L.s. to Col. [] Alexander; [n.p.] 1 Dec 1862., (904); 1s.(1p.)
- Stafford, Leroy Augustus, 1822-1864. A.D.s.; New Orleans, 14 Mar 1853., (905); 1s.(2p.)
  With letters from Harry T. Hayes and D. T. Stafford to Charles Colcock Jones.
- Starke, William Edwin, 1814-1862. MS.L.s. to []; Near Frederick, 8 Sep 1862., (906); 1s.(4p.)
- Steel, William, 1819-1885. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; San Antonio, 18 Jun 1871., (907); 1s.(1p.)
- Steen, A. E. MS.D.s.; Camp Albert Sidney Johnston, 23 Apr 1862., (908); 1s.(2p.)
- Steuart, George Hume, 1828-1903. A.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Gordonsville, 9 Jun 1863., (909); 1s.(2p.)
- Stevens, Alexander Hodgdon, 1789-1869. 3 A.L.s. to St. William H. Woodman:
  - Fort Warren, 21 Aug 1865., (910); 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 28 Sep 1865., (911); 1s.(3p.)
  - Crawfordville, 18 Dec 1865., (912); 1s.(3p.)
- Stevens, Walter Husted, 1827-1867. A.L.s. to William Smith; Richmond, 23 May 1864., (913); 1s.(2p.)
- Stevens, Walter Husted, 1827-1867. A.L.s. to []; Richmond, 15 Apr 1864., (914); 1s.(3p.)
- Stevens, Walter Husted, 1827-1867. MS.D. (unsigned copy); Richmond, 30 Apr 1864., (915); 1s.(2p.)
- Stevenson, Carter Littlepage, 1817-1888. A.L.s. to Samuel Cooper; Charlotte, 5 Mar 1865., (916); 1s.(2p.)
- Stevenson, Carter Littlepage, 1817-1888. A.L.s. to Edmund Winston Pettus; Orangeburg, 11 Feb 1865., (917); 1s.(2p.)
- Stewart, Alexander Peter, 1821-1908. A.L.s. to A. E. Allen; Washington, 9 Feb 1892., (918); 1s.(1p.)
- Stewart, Alexander Peter, 1821-1908. A.L.s. to W. H. McCardle; [n.p.] 26 May 1862., (919); 1s.(2p.)
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Steuart, George Hume, 1828-1903. MS.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Winchester, 15 Nov 1862., (920); 1s.(2p.)
- Stith, C. H. A.L.s. to []; Marmion, 28 Jul [186-?], (921); 1s.(2p.)
- Stovall, Marcellus Augustus, 1818-1895. Signed photograph; [n.p., n.d.], (922); 1s.(1p.)
- Strahl, Otho French, 1831-1864. A.L.s. to [Benjamin Franklin] Cheatham; [n.p.] 6 May 1863., (923); 1s.(2p.)
- Stuart, Charles E. P. A.L.s. to [John Henry] Winder; 27 Aug 1862., (924); 1s.(2p.)
- Stuart, James Ewell Brown, 1833-1864. A.L.s. to Gov. []; Munson's Hill, 12 Sep 1861., (925); 1s.(2p.)
- Stuart, James Ewell Brown, 1833-1864. A.L.s. to []; [n.p.] 8 Mar 1863., (926); 1s.(2p.)
- Swinburne, John, 1820-1889. A.L.s. to [Lafayette] McLaws; [n.p.] 3 Jul 1862., (927); 1s.(2p.)
- Taliaferro, William Booth, 1822-1898. A.L.s. to Col. L. B. Roy; Smithfield, N.C., 4 Apr 1865., (928); 4s.(9p.)
- Tappan, James Camp, 1825-1906. A.L.s. to Maj. [] Maclean; [n.p.] 27 Apr 1863., (929); 1s.(2p.)
- Tappan, James Camp, 1825-1906. MS.L.s. (telegram) to Daniel Ruggles; Jackson, 19 Jun 1862., (930); 1s.(2p.)
- Tappan, James Camp, 1825-1906. MS.D.s.; Camp Bragg, 25 Oct 1863., (931); 1s.(2p.)
- Taylor, Richard, 1826-1879. MS.L.s. to Col. George William Brent; Meridian, 14 Dec 1864., (932); 1s.(4p.)
- Taylor, Richard, 1826-1879. A.L.s. to Capt. [] Butler; Alexandria, 3 Aug 1864., (933); 1s.(4p.)
- Taylor, Thomas Hart, 1825-1901. Endorsement s.; [n.p.] 17 Apr 1863., (934); 1s.(1p.)
- Taylor, W. H. A.L. (unsigned Circular) to [Collett] Seventhorpe; [n.p.] 22 Nov 1864., (935); 1s.(2p.)
- Taylor, W. H. S. MS.L.s. to Col. Gaspard Tochman; [Richmond] 7 Oct 1861., (936); 1s.(2p.)
- Taylor, William H. A.L.s. to John Henry Winder; [n.p.] 26 Mar 1863., (937); 1s.(2p.)
- Terrill, John T. A.D.s.; near Dalton, 4 Dec 1863., (938); 1s.(2p.)
- Terrill, James Barbour, 1838-1864. A.L.s. to [George P. Terrill]; [n.p.] 19 Apr 1864., (939); 1s.(4p.)
  With letter to Charles Colcock Jones from William H. Terrill.
- Terry, William, 1824-1888. A.L.s. to []; Culpepper, 31 Oct 1863., (940); 1s.(2p.)
- Terry, William, 1824-1888. MS.D.s.; [n.p.] 29 Jul 1864., (941); 1s.(2p.)
- Thomas, Bryan Morel, 1836-1905. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Montezuma, Ga., 16 Jul 1871., (942); 1s.(4p.)
- Thomas, Edward Lloyd, 1825-1898. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Covington, Ga. 5 Jun 1871., (943); 1s.(2p.)
- Thompson, Jacob, 1810-1885. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Toronto, 12 Sep 1864., (944); 2s.(8p.)
- Thompson, M. Jeff. A.L.s. to Col. L. A. Maclean; near Lunesport, Ark., 7 Dec 1864., (945); 1s.(2p.)
- Thompson, M. Jeff. A.L.s. to Gideon Johnson Pillow; [n.p.] 16 Aug 1861., (946); 1s.(2p.)
- Thompson, M. Jeff. A.L.s. to Sterling Price; Jonesboro, Ark., 7 May 1863., (947); 1s.(3p.)
- Tilghman, Lloyd, 1816-1863. A.L.s. to William Whann Mackall; Nashville, 7 Jan 1862., (948); 2s.(4p.)
- Tilghman, Lloyd, 1816-1863. A.L.s. to Beriah Magoffin; Paducah, 27 Jun 1861., (949); 2s.(6p.)
- Tilghman, Lloyd, 1816-1863. A.L.s. to Thomas Lowndes Snead; [n.p.] 26 Dec 1862., (950); 1s.(2p.)
- Tochman, Gaspard. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; Richmond, 14 Oct 1861., (951); 1s.(2p.)
- Toombs, Robert, 1810-1885. A.L.s. to William Smith; Washington, 22 Jun 1864., (952); 1s.(3p.)
- Toombs, Robert, 1810-1885. A.L.s. to R. I. Walker; [n.p.] 4 Feb 1849., (953); 1s.(1p.)
- Toon, Thomas Fentress, 1840-1902. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; [n.p.] 12 May 1876., (954); 1s.(1p.)
- Tracy, Edward Dorr, 1833-1863. A.L.s. to []; [n.p.] 28 Sep 1861., (955); 1s.(2p.)
- Trapier, James Heywood, 1815-1865. 2 letters to Col. Edward Manigault:
  - Charleston, 23 Aug 1861., (956); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 17 Nov 1861., (957); 1s.(2p.)
- Trapier, James Heywood, 1815-1865. MS.D.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (958); 1s.(1p.)
- Trenholm, George A. MS.L.s. to Thomas Stanley Bocock; Richmond, 7 Dec 1864., (959); 1s.(2p.)